Event driven strategies are often combined with
由事件推动的策略通常与
fundamental and sentiment factors which help us interpret the significance of the event.
基本面和情感因子一起帮助我们解析事件的重要性
For example, companies typically will release their earnings once every three months.
例如 公司通常每隔三个月发布一次收益报告
The dates are scheduled in advance so there are opportunities to
日期已经提前定好 所以可以在
make trading decisions both before and after the event.
这些事件之前和之后做出交易决策
For pre-event trading, we could use analyst sentiment and fundamentals to
对于事件之前的交易 我们可以根据分析师情感和基本面判断
decide if we expect the earnings release to exceed or fall short of expectations,
收益是超出预期还是低于预期
then we can buy or short before the event.
然后在事件发生之前买入或做空
For example, after analyzing financial statements,
例如 在分析财务报表之后
we may think that the news or analyst sentiment is overly
我们可能认为新闻或分析师情感过于正面
positive and hypothesize that the actual earnings will be less than what's expected.
并认为实际收益将低于预期
So this would be a signal to short or sell.
这可以作为做空或卖出信号
For post-event trading, we could determine whether
对于事件之后的交易
the actual earnings release was better or worse than expected.
我们可以判断实际报告的收益高于还是低于预期
This is also referred to as an earnings surprise.
这称为收益异常
For example, if the actual earnings were above
例如 如果实际收益高于
what was expected based on analyst's ratings and fundamentals,
根据分析师评级和基本面得出的预期收益
then this could potentially be a buy signal.
那么可以是买入信号
We could also combine this with price movements
我们可以在收益报告之后
immediately following the earnings release to
立即根据此信号及价格变化
decide whether other investors considered
判断其他投资者是否将此事件
the event to be positive or negative for the stock price.
看做股价的正面或负面事件
In other words, we could treat the price movements immediately following
也就是说 我们可以根据收益通告之后的价格变化
an earnings announcement as a measure of investor sentiment towards the stock.
判断投资者对股票的情感
To summarize, events in combination with price,
总之 我们可以根据事件与
volume, sentiment and fundamentals may inform a strategy.
价格 交易量 情感及基本面做出决策
One commonly known strategy,
有一个很常见的策略叫做盈余惯性
which doesn't work so well anymore because it is very well known,
这个策略已经不太有用
is the post earnings announcement drift.
因为太有名了
When firms announced earnings,
当企业发布收益报告时
if earnings are above or below expectations,
如果收益高于或低于预期
they're referred to as earning surprises.
则称为收益异常
If we assume an efficient market,
如果我们认为市场很高效
we would expect the market price to adjust
那么在出现收益异常后
quickly and stabilize after an earning surprise.
市场价格会很快调整并平稳下来
However, in reality, is often possible that
但在现实中 经常有可能
prices continued drifting in the same direction,
股价继续以相同的方向漂移
upward for a positive surprise or downward for
在事件发生后约 2 个月内
negative surprise for about two months after the event.
正面收益异常会继续上涨 负面收益异常会继续下跌
Even though this factor is well-known and therefore are not
虽然这个因子已经非常有名
as likely to be used to see abnormal returns,
所以不太可能用于获得超额收益
it is instructive to study this phenomenon to get
但是研究这种现象有助于
some intuition of a market mechanics and behavioral psychology in the markets.
了解市场机制和市场行为心理学